hello everyone my name is greg and i def
staff welcome everyone to episode 9 of
the tactics game in unity
in this episode we will implement
selecting the character
okay before we continue in the updated
asset you will find a new model for the
enemy so let's reduce the character
good
search for constant updates to the
models
it is work in progress so we have to
redo it sometimes i'm terribly sorry
about this
now let's drop the skeleton dude on the
scene which is our new model we need to
make a material for this skeleton
then assign this material to all his
parts except for the arrow
our raw material parts are in the weapon
folder
this bunch of weapons for us to use in
the
in the game in the future all thanks to
declan mohan and his generous support of
this project
this skeleton did have a collection of
new actions it is all related to spear
so now we can implement the spear
actions and because they are using the
same rig with the sword woman those
animations will work on her too
which we will use later on to make an
ability to arm same character with
multiple types of weapons
so now let's add the spear animation to
the skeleton
so add spear idle attack and run to the
character
add a parameter for move and attack
and connect all this animation states
between each other
similar how we did
the sword woman
now let's parent the spear to the
character sword bone
we will need to rename this bone into
something more correct like weapon one
create and attach the material to the
spear
and let's test this
forgot to loop the animations
good
now we want to convert our skeleton
model into the actual character of the
scene remember that the model inside the
character object is just a visual part
the character object itself is the
actual game object which will be
interacting with the world and systems
while the well skeleton model or sword
woman model is just here for
visualizing
so from the gameobject prefab folder
pull and place character object if there
will be a sword woman parented to this
character object delete her and delete
her from the character prefab itself
by opening the prefab by double clicking
on the prefab object in the project
window
and let's prefab the skeleton dude into
character folder
just his model
check the stored woman in my case i
messed up the saved prefab of the sword
woman
delete this prefab and create a new one
specific for the sword woman model
that broke my character on the scene
from now on to build the character you
just simply drop the character object on
the scene and parent the model of the
character from the character folder
rename the character and assign the
target grid
good
this episode is brought to you by
generous support of people on patreon
and members on youtube if you want to
join them link to my patreon in the
description and join button available
right now on youtube
now i want to make it possible to select
the character on the scene by clicking
on the node with the character
select camera and let's disable the grid
control component and move character
component
open grid control script we will
repurpose this script to use for
selecting the objects
on the scene
so let's remove all the parts about
pathfinding out of the script
good
now what we want to do is to get the
grid object in the position our mouse
currently over
this part of the code does exactly this
it shoots the array out of the mouse
position on the screen then it takes the
point of intersection of this ray called
hit that point which then converted into
position on the grid and then we use
this grid position to get to get the
grid object from the grid in that
position
what we want to do now is to move this
part out of the get mouse button down so
all this will be happening every frame
create serialized field called hovering
over and assign it in the update
let's test this
enable the grid control and launch the
game
notice how hovering over field change
the state when you are hovering over the
nodes on the grid with objects in them
good
now what we want to do is to add a new
component to the character prefab called
selectablegrid object
this component should be
present on any grid object which you
want to make possible to select
so far we only have character and they
should be possible to select
later on we might introduce new grid
objects which may end up impossible to
be selected by the player for example
items on the ground while being grid
object will not be possible to select by
the player
or maybe in your game you will want to
make it possible to select item on the
ground and in that case you will have to
just add this component to the object
so now we want to select the object open
grid control and in the get mouse button
down store the selectable grid object
into a new field
if we are not hovering over any object
we shouldn't be able to select anything
so just add exit gate here
and let's test this
now if i hover over the
character and press left mouse button e
it will select the character into
selected object field
good and let's hypothetically say that
one of the character doesn't have
selectable grid object for whatever
reason
now if i try to click on that object it
will select nothing
but right now no matter what i do i
can't deselect the character
to nullify this selection let's use
right mouse button and if it is pressed
nullify selection
good
now let's polish our code a little
let's extract all this code into
separate methods
with self-descriptive names
one more touch before we conclude this
episode in the hover over object check
this part will always be executed no
matter what which is not very efficient
instead we want to do this part only if
the position we are currently hovering
over has changed so create a new
variable called currentgrid position of
type vector2 in
then inside the hover over object check
if the grid position equals to current
grid position it will mean that we're
still hovering over the same grip
position
so we don't need to execute everything
else in this method and we should exit
good this is it for this episode if you
have any questions or any ideas about
code please leave your comment below if
you're interested in seeing what will
come out of this please subscribe if you
want to support further you can find my
patreon in the description special thank
you to andrew v long and this old hash
do for their generous support with best
regards see you in the next episode
you